### **Zhan Wang**

Department of Agricultural Economics, Purdue University
Room 645, Krannert Building, 403 Mitch Daniels Blvd, West Lafayette, IN 47907
<a href="mailto:zhanwang@purdue.edu">zhanwang@purdue.edu</a> | <a href="https://wangzhan90.com">https://wangzhan90.com</a> | <a href="mailto:(765) 701-7418">(765) 701-7418</a>

# **Research Interests**

My research focuses on the interactions between land use, agricultural production and environment protection, in particular the global, national and gridded impacts on the agriculture-land-environment system with general / partial equilibrium models and geospatial data.

# **Education**

Ph.D in Agricultural Economics, Purdue University, USA	Aug 2018 – Jul 2023
Master of Environmental Management, Duke University, USA	Aug 2012 – May 2014
Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science Bachelor of Science in Psychology (Dual degree) Peking University, China	Sep 2008 – Jul 2012 Sep 2009 – Jul 2012
Professional Experience	
Post-Doctoral Research Associate Department of Agricultural Economics, Purdue University, USA	Aug 2023 – Present
Graduate Research Assistant Department of Agricultural Economics, Purdue University, USA	Aug 2018 – Jul 2023
Research Assistant Global Health Research Center, Duke Kunshan University, China	Dec 2014 – Apr 2017

# **Peer-reviewed Journal Articles**

**Publications** 

- 1. **Wang, Zhan**, and Thomas Hertel. "SMART Handout: An Innovative Tool to Empower Applied General Equilibrium Teaching." *Journal of Global Economic Analysis* 9, no. 1 (2024): 45-61. <a href="https://doi.org/10.21642/JGEA.090102AF">https://doi.org/10.21642/JGEA.090102AF</a>
- 2. **Wang, Zhan**, Geraldo B. Martha Jr, Jing Liu, Cicero Z. Lima, and Thomas W. Hertel. "Planned expansion of transportation infrastructure in Brazil has implications for the pattern of agricultural production and carbon emissions." *Science of The Total Environment* 928 (2024): 172434. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.172434">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.172434</a>
- 3. Zhu, Gangjiao, Rahul Malhotra, Shangzhi Xiong, Xinyue Chen, Mingyang Zhang, You Wu, Enying Gong, **Zhan Wang**, Xiangyang Tian, Weixia Peng, Truls Østbye, and Lijing L Yan. "Community Efficacy for Non-Communicable Disease Management and Medication Adherence: The Sequential Mediating Role of Self-Efficacy and Depressive

- Symptoms." *Patient preference and adherence* (2023): 3421-3433. https://doi.org/10.2147/PPA.S436419
- 4. Chen, Shu, Lei Guo, **Zhan Wang**, Wenhui Mao, Yanfeng Ge, Xiaohua Ying, Jing Fang et al. "Current situation and progress toward the 2030 health-related Sustainable Development Goals in China: A systematic analysis." *PLoS medicine* 16, no. 11 (2019). https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1002975
- 5. Li, Niying, **Zhan Wang**\*, and Keith Dear. "Violence against health professionals and facilities in China: evidence from criminal litigation records." *Journal of forensic and legal medicine* 67 (2019): 1-6. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jflm.2019.07.006">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jflm.2019.07.006</a>
- 6. **Wang, Zhan**, Enying Gong, Weixia Peng, Jiaying Chen, Xiangyang Tian, Shangzhi Xiong, and Lijing Yan\*. "Community empowerment for the prevention and control of non-communicable diseases." (in Chinese) *Chinese General Practice* 22, no. 10 (2019): 1153.
- 7. **Wang, Zhan**, Niying Li\*, Mengsi Jiang, Keith Dear, and Chee-Ruey Hsieh. "Records of medical malpractice litigation: a potential indicator of health-care quality in China." *Bulletin of the World Health Organization* 95, no. 6 (2017): 430. <a href="https://doi.org/10.2471/BLT.16.179143">https://doi.org/10.2471/BLT.16.179143</a>
- 8. **Wang, Zhan**, and Keith Dear\*. "Region and firm level determinants of environmental regulation violations: An empirical study in Chongqing, China." *Journal of cleaner production* 141 (2017): 1011-1022. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2016.09.090
- 9. Liu, Feifei, Lijing Yan, **Zhan Wang**, Yuanan Lu, Yuanyuan Chu, Xiangyu Li, Yisi Liu, Dongsheng Rui, Shaofa Nie, and Hao Xiang\*. "Metformin therapy and risk of colorectal adenomas and colorectal cancer in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis." *Oncotarget* 8, no. 9 (2017): 16017. https://doi.org/10.18632/oncotarget.13762

# **Conference proceedings**

- 1. Haqiqi, Iman, **Zhan Wang**, Srabashi Ray, Uris Baldos, Jing Liu, and Thomas Hertel. "Market-Mediated Effects: What Are they? And why are They Important for Geospatial Analysis of Sustainability Policies." *I-GUIDE Forum 2023 Harnessing the Geospatial Data Revolution for Sustainability Solutions* (2023). <a href="https://doi.org/10.5703/1288284317682">https://doi.org/10.5703/1288284317682</a>
- 2. Fraysse, Elizabeth A., Thomas W. Hertel, **Zhan Wang**, and Iman Haqiqi. "SIMPLE-G In the Classroom and the Cloud." *I-GUIDE Forum 2023 Harnessing the Geospatial Data Revolution for Sustainability Solutions* (2023). <a href="https://doi.org/10.5703/1288284317668">https://doi.org/10.5703/1288284317668</a>

#### **Commentary**

1. Dear, Keith\*, and **Zhan Wang**. "Climate and health: mortality attributable to heat and cold." The Lancet 386, no. 9991 (2015): 320-322. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60897-2">https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60897-2</a>

### **Book chapter**

- 1. **Wang, Zhan**. "Chapter 15: The Role of Transportation Infrastructure Expansion in the Transmission of Global Price Shocks to the Brazilian Economy." in *SIMPLE-G: A Gridded Economic Approach to Sustainability Analysis of the Earth's Land and Water Resources*. Haqiqi and Hertel (eds). Springer Publishing, 2024.
- 2. Wang, Zhan, Jiwei Chen, Yujiao Jiang, Yunyi Li, Lina Song, Yuanqing Zhu, Jialiang Liang. "The life condition of ecological migrants in Ordos, Inner Mongolia." in *Environment Watch: The fifth anniversary collection of students' social practices from the College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Peking University (in Chinese)*, The editorial board of social practices from the College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Peking University (eds). The Publishing House of Electronics Industry, 2013.

### **Working papers**

- 1. "Soybean Trade between the United States, Brazil and China: Interactions between Global Trade Flow and Gridded Agricultural and Environmental impacts", with Thomas Hertel
  - Accepted for presentation at the 2024 AAEA conference
- 2. "Impact of China's South-North Water Transfer Project on Agriculture: Integrated Analysis of the Food-Land-Water System", with Jing Liu, Qingyu Feng, Shanxia Sun, Thomas Hertel, Dominique van der Mensbrugghe and Matthew Huber
- 3. "Climate Change, Irrigation Expansion and Impacts on Agriculture Production: An Integrated Multi-Scale Analysis of Brazil by 2050", with Geraldo B. Martha Jr., Jing Liu and Cicero Zanetti de Lima
- 4. "Nexus between Economic Growth, Pollution Control and Natural Ecosystem: Theory and Empirical Evidence"

# **Teaching Experience**

<b>Teaching assistant</b> AGEC618 (PhD level) "Applied General Equilibrium Analysis" Purdue University	2023
Instructor Short Course in Multi-scale Analysis of Sustainability Purdue University	2022, 2024
Lab instructor Biostatistics and Epidemiology for Global Health (Master level) (on data analysis with STATA), Duke Kunshan University	2015 – 2017

# **Conference Presentations**

GTAP 27th Annual Conference, Fort Collins, CO	2024
I-GUIDE forum, New York, NY	2023
AAEA Annual Meeting, Washington, D.C	2023
AGU Fall Meeting 2022, Chicago, IL (poster)	2022
AAEA Annual Meeting, Anaheim, CA	2022
GTAP 25th Annual Conference, online	2022
AAEA & WAEA Joint Annual Meeting, Austin, TX and online	2021
GTAP 24th Annual Conference, online	2021
GTAP 23rd Annual Conference, online	2020

# **Reviewer for Journals and Conferences**

Journal of the Agricultural and Applied Economics Association

China Agricultural Economic Review

Global Food Security

Environment, Development and Sustainability

Journal of Forensic and Legal Medicine

Human Resources for Health

GTAP Annual Conferences  $(25^{th},\,26^{th},\,27^{th})$ 

# Training / Workshops

I-GUIDE summer school, Boulder, CO	2023
NVIDIA Fundamentals of Deep Learning	2022
Trustworthy AI for Environmental Science	2021
Berkeley Sloan Summer School in Environmental and Energy Economics	2021

# **Awards and Honors**

Grad Student Poster Competition (2 <sup>nd</sup> place) of AgEcon department, Purdue Univers	ity 2022
Dean's Award for Special Contribution, Duke Kunshan University	2017
Degree Marshal for Nicholas School of the Environment, Duke University	2014
Outstanding Graduate of Beijing, Peking University	2012
Cyrus Tang Scholarship, Peking University 2	008 - 2012

# **Software Skills**

R, GEMPACK, QGIS, Python

# Language

Chinese (native), English (fluent)

(Last updated: June 2024)